thenourishinggourmet.com 2018-12-25

# Privacy

This privacy policy sets out how The Nourishing Gourmet uses and protects any information that you give while using www.TheNourishingGourmet.com

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.  
The Nourishing Gourmet may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 12/3/2014  
What we collect  
We may collect the following information:  
• contact information including email address  
• demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests  
• other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

What we do with the information we gather  
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:  
• We may use the information to improve our products and services.  
• We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.  
• We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

**Security**  
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**How our Advertisers, including Gourmet Ads Uses Cookies, and Advertisers use traffic log cookies**  
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.  
Traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps advertisers analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. Companies only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.  
.A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.  
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**Affiliates**  
To ensure that commissions are earned on affiliate links, cookies are typically served when you click on a link. This is simply to ensure that I am given a percentage of any products sold through my recommendation.  
**Advertising**  
Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is http://www.gourmetads.com. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.  
Links to other websites  
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.  
Controlling your personal information  
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:  
• whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes

• if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.  
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

**RSS & Email Subscriptions**

This website records information about how people access the RSS feeds, but does not collect any personally identifying information from or about RSS subscribers. The website’s feed services collect the e-mail addresses of individuals that subscribe to the RSS feed via e-mail. Individual information about subscribers to my blog’s feeds are held in strict confidence; I will not release or disclose any specific subscriber information under any circumstances, unless required by law. Aggregated information stripped of any personally identifiable information may be disclosed.

**Comments**  
Comments are the responsibility of the commenter. I reserve the right to remove or edit comments at my discretion. This includes but is not limited to comments containing profanity, self promotion, harassment, threats or spam of any sort. Site URLs (if provided) are published along with comments. E-mail addresses are required with the submission of comments but are not disclosed, unless the commenter deliberately does so him/herself by entering the e-mail address in the main comment box in addition to the box clearly labeled for the e-mail address.

**Links to Third Party Websites**  
I have included links on this site to other websites and resources for your use and reference. I am not responsible for the privacy policies on these websites. You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from my own.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**  
The contents of this statement may be altered at any time, at my discretion.

**Opt Out**  
For information about opting out of Gourmet Ads and ad serving partners please visit http://www.gourmetads.com/about/privacy-policy  
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us.

The following two tabs change content below.

  * Bio
  * Latest Posts

I love beautiful and simple food that is nourishing to the body and the soul. I wrote Fresh: Nourishing Salads for All Seasons and Ladled: Nourishing Soups for All Seasons as another outlet of sharing this love of mine. I also love sharing practical tips on how to make a real food diet work on a real life budget. Find me online elsewhere by clicking on the icons below!
